Kevin J. McIntyre

kevin70@yahoo.com web:nwice.com

Data

MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Postgres, Redis, DynamoDB

Infrastructure

Amazon AWS, Security Admin, System Admin

Expertise

Android, Hibernate, GWT, J2EE, JQuery, JSON, NodeJS, Python, Qt, Rest, RequireJS, Spring, Twisted, WebSocket, Web Services, XSLT

Servers

Apache, Jboss, Nginx, Tomcat, Twisted

Tools

ADT, Eclipse, Git/ SVN, Jenkins, Junit, Linux, Maven, Trial, Ubuntu

Objective

Seeking positions within software development acting as lead developer, systems architect, or operations principle.

Summary

Beginning 1996-2000 my experience was in coding all aspects of the web with ASP, Perl, Cold Fusion, and MSSQL. 2000-2008 I focused primarily on open source technologies with an emphasis on Linux, apache, java/ J2EE development. Since, I've deepened my utilization of open source software, delivering and securing solutions to any need.

As a member of a team and part of an organization, I've always tried to be a fun dependable co-worker, believing that successful software is a combination of clear objectives and team cohesion.

My development philosophy is tool based, as a means of useful software utilized during all phases of the development cycle; that can act in Agile aspects - delivering early and often, but also as a means of research and selection, by establishing thresholds/boundaries that yield into operation metrics/visibility. Ultimately tools acting as infrastructure that are non-pollutive with regards to ease of maintenance and predictable upgrade cycles.

Most recently I have pursued software projects within personal interest to further my learning of cloud based development, and reactive based programming.



Athleets Junkeet Pokertalon

Tweet streams with contextualization - sports, politics, poker powered by Twisted, QT, Autobahn, DynamoDB, S3, Cloudfront.

card.nwice.com www.blackjack4all.com Automated War

Work exploring gameplay at the intersection of javascript, 2d-context, and mutual simulation. Written in JQuery, RequireJS, Node.js with runtime components rendering in 2d canvas.

Scewpt SMTP Morning Google

Indisposable email via Amazon AWS, SMTP Command/Control system to EC2 job creation running within Amazon Web Service.

Professional Experience

Consultant *Esri* 4/2013 – 7/2013

Java architecture on ecommerce portion of ArcGIS for Developers. Multi-tiered maven project, bridging Salesforce API with Spring and Java Jersey, serving rest-based json to javascript clients. Included components: Memcached, Amazon ElastiCache, TestNG, and Java Jackson. Working environment was Agile based with an emphasis on test driven development.

Senior Developer

Green Charge Networks

8/2011 - 4/2013

Key contributor on flagship products Greenstation, and GridSynergy for Green Charge Networks. Lead development on prototype of event-driven embedded system controller using Python and Twisted. Device provided mitigation and curtailment of energy usage through control of inverter battery, photovoltaic, and electric vehicle charging systems. Monitoring was provided via reporting to Redis, and was controlled via GridSynergy network operations center, securely hosted in Amazon Web Services. Developed real-time charting system using Google Visualization, a tool used extensively during testing, operations, and new business development. Managed the release of multiple iterations of the software across the installation sites at 7-11, and Avis car rental. Contributor to corporate IP, authoring several patents on grid-tied battery control systems. Contributing developer on network operation J2EE software, using Maven, Tomcat, Hibernate, Spring, and Google Web Toolkit.

Java Architect Freelancers Union 4/2008 – 2/2011

Lead developer on a medical portal for the Freelancers Union. Key member during project planning phase, advising on software infrastructure, researching solutions, and authoring project documentation. Implemented project using Eclipse, SVN, Maven, Xdoclet, MantisBT targeting Linux/CentOS running Apache, Jboss 4.2.3, and Oracle 11g. Developed standards-based enterprise application with hibernate model, a business-tier, and servlet/jsp controllers/views. Application featured services that serialized third-party EDI file into a data warehouse. Web application featured SSO modules to view patient claims information on third-party websites written in OpenSAML and SAML 2.0. Developed administrative web application for call center representatives to view enrollment changes, and manage portal users. Also, performed key roles through two billing/enrollment vendor transitions, contributing as quality assurance tester, business liaison, and lead developer spanning the lifecycle of the projects.

Senior Consultant Crunch Fitness 10/2006 – 3/2008

Engineered enterprise Swing application for an industry leading health club chain. Application featured JNLP WebStart client brokering calls via EJB SessionBeans to a server, running Jboss 4.0.5 and MSSQL 2005. Took ownership of source code (2500 source files/1800 sql scripts) and release cycle from 3rd-party vendor, responsible for all facets of development. Established a test environment, installed tracking software to manage bugs and feature requests. Coded to J2EE standards, improving security using IP and MAC addressing, resolving cross-country latency issues while implementing or fixing bugs/features. Acted as DBA: modified schema to implement new features, wrote stored procedures using cursors and common table expressions. Additional duties included Cold Fusion development on the corporate sales website, and ASP.net development on the public facing website.

Lead software development at lamplify.com. Server administrator for linux servers running Apache2 (mod_php & OSCommerce), Jboss, Ruby, and MySQL. Project lead for embedded flash player initiative, and lead developer of associated reporting tool, providing key metrics such as registrations, purchases, and downloads. Lead development on co-branded storefronts (HarperCollins) written using Eclipse, Maven, and Xdoclet. Coded servlets, listeners, and taglibs, utilizing a custom templating engine. Developed deployment tool enabling designers and content managers to easily tweak, test and deploy each storefront. Additional duties included PHP scripting on fulfillment system, and development of media tools website.

Software Consultant Blueprint 1/2004 – 2/2005

Consultant to Blueprint , a pharmaceutical branding company. Lead developer of application connecting doctors and patients. Established a data center, and lead development through multiple life-cycles, working with graphic designers and a junior developer. Written with Xdoclet to be application server and database agnostic, and ran seamlessly on Jboss/MySQL and WebLogic/Oracle infrastructure. Additional duties included work on client websites such as Rockport , and DFKing.

Consultant NYC Department of Probation 12/2002 – 1/2004

Consultant to NYC Department of Probation, lead developer on automated probationer check-in system, managing 4 junior developers. Application utilized touch-screen monitor, and active-x controllers for web-cameras, palm-scanners, and printing. Developed using with Eclipse, Ant, and Xdoclet using remote EJB CMP Beans connecting to Informix database, JMS topics for probationer alerts, unit testing with JUnit, and MVC architecture with Struts form handling.

Lead Developer Volatile Media 3/1999 – 8/2000

Lead developer for Volatile Media, owner of multimedia start-up EZCD.com. Responsible for production infrastructure of a custom CD burning service, featuring samples of music as well as game demos for creating a custom mixed media CD. Developed websites using MSSQL, Cold Fusion, and java services supporting back-end manufacturing. Developed mailing-list, calendar, and content management tools allowing artists to promote their music. Responsible for interviewing/hiring junior developers and managed aspects of a small office including networking, Exchange server, and ISP relationships.

Developer Lexitrans 10/1996 – 5/1999

Developer for Lexitrans, an online credit card transaction company. Coded and maintained state of the art membership billing system supporting 300,000 active members with real-time, and batch transactions using Cold Fusion, MSSQL, and X.25 communications for credit card authorization/transaction. Lead developer of call center software employing 150 people authoring html forms, db schema, stored procedures, and nightly scheduled tasks. Participated in data center re-location and conversion from Cold Fusion/MSSQL to ATG Dynamo/Oracle.

Education